https://www.salvationarmy.org.au/about-us/governance-and-policy/privacy-policy/

The Salvation Army URL has changed to salvationarmy.org.auFind out more
Home
Need Help?
Their Turn To Receive Help
Giving Janet The Support She Needed To Free Herself From The Debt
Wills and Bequests
Information for Solicitors (including Bequest Wording)
XView Wishes Cart0
Need Help?
› Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy The Salvation Army Privacy Policy APP- Australia
Last Updated: 29 March 2019. The electronic version of this policy is the approved and current version. Any printed version is uncontrolled and may not be current.
Personal Information
You should read this policy before providing us with any personal information or before using our website. By providing us with your personal information or by using the website, you are confirming your agreement to the policies and procedures described in this policy. From time to time it may be necessary for us to review and revise this policy. We reserve the right to change this policy at any time.
The Salvation Army as an Organisation
Protecting your privacy is fundamental to the way we care for people. For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, ‘The Salvation Army’ (and ‘we’, ‘our’, ‘us’) means:
The Salvation Army (being the unincorporated worldwide religious and charitable association)
The Salvation Army (New South Wales) Property Trust Act 1929 (NSW)
Salvation Army (Queensland) Property Trust Act 1930 (Qld)
Salvation Army (Tasmania) Property Trust Act 1930 (Tas)
The Salvation Army (Victoria) Property Trust Act 1930 (Vic)
The Salvation Army (South Australia) Property Trust Act 1931 (SA)
The Salvation Army (Western Australia) Property Trust Act 1931 (WA)
Salvation Army Property Trust Act 1934 (ACT)
Salvation Army (Northern Territory) Property Trust Act 2002 (NT)
Any organisations or bodies corporate owned or operated by any of the bodies above
Your privacy is important to us
The Salvation Army is committed to upholding the Australian Privacy Principles contained in the Privacy Act 1988. We recognise the importance of privacy and community awareness regarding the collection, use, disclosure and security of personal and sensitive information which we may collect during the course of our many functions. This Privacy Policy sets out how we manage your personal and sensitive information and protect your privacy.
The information we collect and hold
The Salvation Army performs many functions and provides a wide range of services and programs across Australia. We will only collect personal and sensitive information that is necessary for us to carry out these functions and provide these services and programs. The type of information we may collect, hold and use, varies depending on the purpose for which it is collected but may include the following (amongst others):
Supporters - as a supporter of The Salvation Army’s mission and activities, we may need to collect your name and contact details. As a valued financial supporter of our fundraising activities, we may also need to collect your bank account or credit card details.
Service recipients, program participants or clients of our other services - as a recipient of, or participant in, one of our many services and programs (such as aged care, recovery, welfare, employment assistance, social or other services and programs), we may need to collect your name and contact details, information regarding your health, income status, religious beliefs, ethnicity and emergency contact details.
Customers - as a customer at one of our many stores, we may need to collect your name and contact details at the time of purchase or in connection with your donation of goods.
Personnel - as an officer, employee, volunteer or member of The Salvation Army, we may need to collect information about your name and contact details, bank account and taxation details, qualifications, previous experience and emergency contact details.
How we collect and keep safe your personal and sensitive information
How we collect and store personal and sensitive information varies depending on the purpose for which it is collected. We may collect your personal information:
Directly from you, either in person, over the phone or by email
From third parties where you have specifically authorised us to do so
Through our website including through forms on our website.
We will always collect your personal information directly from you unless it is impracticable to do so. This would usually be done in person, over the telephone or by email. Examples may include:
Copies of your written correspondence with us
Copies of receipts and/or transaction records in relation to your financial support of our fundraising activities
Copies of your application form, request for assistance and/or other associated documents (including documents generated during your participation in a program with, or otherwise during your interactions with us) and information that you may provide to us in relation to one of the many services and programs we offer
Copies of your volunteer agreement or employment agreement and any associated documents and information you provide to us in connection with your volunteering for or employment with The Salvation Army.
We may keep copies of the above documents (in physical and/or electronic form, at our election) as is necessary to carry out our functions and provide our services and programs. All personal and sensitive information is securely stored at all times by us or an authorised external service provider and only authorised people will have access to the above documents and information.
Why we collect, hold and use personal and sensitive information
We may collect, hold, use and disclose personal and sensitive information for purposes necessary to carry out our functions and provide our services and programs. Generally, these purposes include:
To keep in contact with you as a supporter of The Salvation Army and to inform you about the role and extent of our work and mission
To manage our fundraising activities and for taxation record-keeping purposes associated with your donation to The Salvation Army
To assess your welfare needs and to provide you with the welfare and community services and assistance we offer
To provide you with the necessary care and assistance during your time as a resident of, or recipient of services from, one of our services, centres or facilities (such as aged care centres, recovery services, crisis accommodation services, etc.)
To provide you with the services requested by you from us
To facilitate and manage your purchase from, or donation of goods to, one of our stores
To comply with necessary business and accounting standards
To comply with our reporting obligations to the Australian Taxation Office and other government agencies and public sector bodies
To facilitate and manage your employment relationship or volunteer arrangement with The Salvation Army
We are committed to maintaining your privacy and we will only use your personal and sensitive information for a permitted purpose for which we have collected the information. There is no obligation for you to provide us with any of your personal information however if you choose not to provide us with your personal information, we may not be able to provide you with the services that you require. You have the option of not identifying yourself or using a pseudonym when dealing with us in relation to a particular matter, unless we believe it is impracticable to do so in the circumstances. If you wish to deal with us in this manner, you must tell us in writing so that we can consider if your request is practicable.
How we may share your information
If necessary to carry out our functions and provide our services and programs, we may need to disclose your personal and sensitive information to external service providers (such as information technology service providers, legal service providers, mailing houses, call centres, other community service providers, etc.) and other organisations. We will only share your personal and sensitive information in accordance with your express consent and instructions, subject to the exclusions set out in the Australian Privacy Principles, or in accordance with the specific Privacy Notice provided to you by us at or near the time of collection of your personal and sensitive information. We do not supply our database information to other marketing organisations not acting on our behalf.
How we use Google Remarketing
We do not collect any individual personal information on visitors to our website without your knowledge. We do collect non-personal information that allows us to log information about visitors to our website for statistical purposes, such as:
The number of unique sessions as identified by server address and top-level domain name (e.g. .com, .gov, .org, etc.)
The number of page hits
The pages accessed or downloaded by session
The type of browser being used
The length of time spent on the site and on particular pages
The device being used (e.g. desktop or mobile)
The type of mobile device being used (e.g. iPhone 4)
In addition:
We have implemented and use Display Advertising
We use Remarketing with Google to advertise online
Third-party vendors, including Google, show our ads on sites across the Internet
We and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimise, and serve ads based on someone's past behaviour to our website
Users can opt out by utilising Google's Opt-out Browser Add-on (https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) and/or Ads Preferences Manager (www.google.com/settings/ads).
What international disclosure do we make
The Salvation Army is an international movement with a presence in over 120 countries. While every effort is made to keep personal and sensitive information we hold in Australia only, in order to carry out our functions and provide our programs and services we may need to disclose personal and sensitive information to overseas recipients, unless expressly prohibited by law. In the unlikely event such disclosure is required, it will generally involve disclosure to international territories of The Salvation Army and only to the extent necessary to carry out our functions and provide our programs and services.
How you can access and seek correction of your personal and sensitive information
You have the right to access your personal and sensitive information, subject to some exceptions allowed by law. If you would like to access or seek correction of your personal and sensitive information, please contact our Privacy Office at the contact details below. For security reasons you will be asked to put your request in writing. To enable us to verify your request we require you to advise the following:
Your full name
Address
Contact phone number
The relevant department or service (if known) that your request relates to
There is no application fee for making a request to access your personal and sensitive information. While we do not normally charge for providing individuals with access to their personal and sensitive information, we reserve the right to charge you for our reasonable costs in complying with a request for access. These costs will not be excessive.
How you can complain about a breach of the Australian Privacy Principles
We are committed to protecting your privacy and upholding the Australian Privacy Principles. If you believe we have breached the Australian Privacy Principles please contact our Privacy Office with your concerns at the contact details below. We take all complaints very seriously and we will endeavour to respond to your complaint and address your concerns as soon as reasonably practicable.
How we comply with the Notifiable Data Breaches Scheme
We will notify you in the event your personal information is involved in a data breach that is likely to result in serious harm. This notification will include recommendations about the steps you should take in response to the breach. We will also notify The Australian Information Commissioner of eligible data breaches. Each suspected data breach reported to us will be assessed to determine whether it is likely to result in serious harm, and as a result require notification.
How you can contact our Privacy Office
We welcome and appreciate your feedback or comments in relation to our Privacy Policy and the collection of personal and sensitive information. If you have any questions in relation to privacy please contact our Privacy Office for your state or territory at the contact details below.
Privacy OfficeThe Salvation ArmyPO Box 479 BLACKBURN VIC 3130Email: privacy@aus.salvationarmy.orgTelephone: 1800 961 088 between 9.00am & 4.30pm Monday - Friday
In this section:
